<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Overview on SLU SOC 4650 and 5650</title>
    <link>/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Overview on SLU SOC 4650 and 5650</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2019 Christopher G. Prener</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Git and GitHub</title>
      <link>/docs/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/git/</guid>
      <description>Meta &amp;nbsp; Spring 2019  &amp;nbsp; Draft  &amp;nbsp; 2018-12-06 
Key Topics &amp;nbsp; GitHub
Overview Much of our interaction this semester outside of class will utilize GitHub.com (or just &amp;ldquo;GitHub&amp;rdquo;). GitHub is a web service that is a social network for programmers, developers, data scientists, researchers, and academics. It is also a tool for collaborating on projects, especially projects that involve writing code.
We&amp;rsquo;ll use GitHub as an alternative to Blackboard, the course management system that students are typically familiar with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Approaching Coursework</title>
      <link>/docs/course-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/course-approach/</guid>
      <description>Meta &amp;nbsp; Spring 2019  &amp;nbsp; Draft  &amp;nbsp; 2018-01-05 
Overview Students have varying experiences learning computational techniques. For some, the math and programming that are the foundation for modern data science techniques come naturally. For others, being introduced to these concepts can be an anxiety producing experience. I am fond the phrase &amp;ldquo;your mileage will vary&amp;rdquo; for describing these differences - no two students have the exact same experience taking a computational methods course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Help</title>
      <link>/docs/getting-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/getting-help/</guid>
      <description>Meta &amp;nbsp; Spring 2019  &amp;nbsp; Draft  &amp;nbsp; 2018-12-05 
Key Topics &amp;nbsp; R  reprex
Overview One of the biggest challenges for students first learning tools like R, ArcGIS, and LaTeX is dealing with the inevitable speed-bumps and errors that come along with scientific computing. Remember, first and foremost, that these tools are not consumer software. They do not always &amp;ldquo;just work&amp;rdquo;, to borrow a turn of phrase from Steve Jobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Enough Research Practices</title>
      <link>/docs/good-enough-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/good-enough-practices/</guid>
      <description>Meta &amp;nbsp; Spring 2019  &amp;nbsp; Draft  &amp;nbsp; 2018-12-05 
Overview This section introduces some of the core concepts that support sociospatial data science works. The title of the chapter takes inspiration from a recent article titled Good enough practices in scientific computing (Wilson et al. 2017). The authors note in their introduction that scientific computing advice can sometimes be both overwhelming and focused on tools that are inaccessible to many analysts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture-01 - Course Introduction</title>
      <link>/docs/lecture-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/lecture-01/</guid>
      <description>Meta &amp;nbsp; Spring 2019  &amp;nbsp; Full  &amp;nbsp; 2019-01-22 
Key Topics &amp;nbsp; Analysis development  base &amp;nbsp; Cartography  here &amp;nbsp; Interactive maps  leaflet  magrittr &amp;nbsp; R  readr  sf
Resources &amp;nbsp; View on Syllabus  &amp;nbsp; View on GitHub  &amp;nbsp; View Recording  &amp;nbsp; Exercise - Email  &amp;nbsp; Exercise - Shaw Crime  &amp;nbsp; Functions 
Lecture Slides    Leaflet Basics As a way to get to know R and RStudio, we&amp;rsquo;ll be working with the R package leaflet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opinionated Tools and Processes</title>
      <link>/docs/opinionated-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/opinionated-tools/</guid>
      <description>Meta &amp;nbsp; Spring 2019  &amp;nbsp; Draft  &amp;nbsp; 2018-12-09 
Key Topics &amp;nbsp; Analysis development
Overview The methods introduced in this course are meant to be &amp;ldquo;opinionated&amp;rdquo; - we start from a strong conception about what &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; geospatial data science looks like. I want to introduce a high level definition of opinionated processes here, and discuss how these ideas might fit into previous coursework you&amp;rsquo;ve taken as well as this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Your Work</title>
      <link>/docs/protecting-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/protecting-work/</guid>
      <description>Meta &amp;nbsp; Spring 2019  &amp;nbsp; Draft  &amp;nbsp; 2018-12-05 
Overview One of the biggest challenges to with doing computational work is that it requires a high degree of organization. Our approaches to file management on computers are often haphazard, with Documents and Downloads folders filled with disorganized files or a Desktop covered in dozens of files. Perhaps this has worked in the past, but that approach (or lack thereof) will fail students in Introduction to Geographic Information Science (SOC 4650&amp;frasl;5650) and Quantitative Analysis: Applied Inferential Statistics (SOC 4930&amp;frasl;5050).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Onboarding</title>
      <link>/docs/course-onboarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/course-onboarding/</guid>
      <description>Meta &amp;nbsp; Spring 2019  &amp;nbsp; Full  &amp;nbsp; 2018-01-05 
Resources Onboarding Checklist 
Overview Before you begin the semester, there are a number of things that you should do to help set yourself up for success. All of the applicable sections below should be completed before our first class on January 14th. Before you do anything else, though, you should read through the Syllabus. Make sure you have a good sense of what is required for the course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Preview</title>
      <link>/docs/course-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/course-preview/</guid>
      <description>Meta &amp;nbsp; Spring 2019  &amp;nbsp; Full  &amp;nbsp; 2018-01-05 
Key Topics &amp;nbsp; Analysis development &amp;nbsp; Interactive maps &amp;nbsp; Open data &amp;nbsp; Reproducibility
Open Data and GIS in Los Angeles One of the course learning outcomes is titled &amp;ldquo;GISc and Public Policy&amp;rdquo;. Much of the data that we will use this semester is available to us because governmental agencies at the Federal, state, and local levels have published it and made it accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Software</title>
      <link>/docs/course-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/course-software/</guid>
      <description>Meta &amp;nbsp; Spring 2019  &amp;nbsp; Draft  &amp;nbsp; 2018-12-04 
Overview This course is built primarily around a set of four software applications - ArcGIS Pro, the programming language R, the graphical user interface for R called RStudio, and GitHub Desktop. As I noted on the course onboarding page, there are two choices for accessing software. Please read through the course onboarding page page carefully and make the decisions you think are best for you - either using your own computer or using a lab computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating RMarkdown Documents</title>
      <link>/docs/rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description> Meta &amp;nbsp; Spring 2019  &amp;nbsp; Draft  &amp;nbsp; 2018-12-05 
Key Topics  knitr &amp;nbsp; Markdown &amp;nbsp; R &amp;nbsp; Reproducibility  rmarkdown &amp;nbsp; RStudio  testDriveR
Resources RMarkdown Cheatsheet 
Overview This document assumes you are already comfortable with the content in the Writing in Markdown doc.
 Literate Programming RMarkdown Basics Assignment Layout Code Chunks Enviornment Considerations Working Directory Considerations </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project</title>
      <link>/docs/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/project/</guid>
      <description>Meta &amp;nbsp; Spring 2019  &amp;nbsp; Draft  &amp;nbsp; 2018-12-04</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic Index</title>
      <link>/docs/topic-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/topic-index/</guid>
      <description> Overview A-D  Analysis development (Fundamentals Articles [a, b, c], Course Preview, Lecture-01)  E-H I-L  Interactive maps (Course Preview)  M-P  Open data (Course Preview)  Q-T  Reproducibility (Course Preview)  U-Z </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing in Markdown</title>
      <link>/docs/markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/markdown/</guid>
      <description>Meta &amp;nbsp; Spring 2019  &amp;nbsp; Draft  &amp;nbsp; 2018-12-05 
Key Topics &amp;nbsp; GitHub &amp;nbsp; Markdown
Resources GitHub Mastering Markdown  RMarkdown Reference Guide 
Basics Markdown is a simple markup language. Markup languages are used to give computer programs directions on how particular blocks of text should be processed. Markdown was developed in 2004 by writer and developer John Gruber. Gruber describes Markdown on his website:
 Markdown is intended to be as easy-to-read and easy-to-write as is feasible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture-02 - ArcGIS Pro Overview</title>
      <link>/docs/lecture-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/lecture-02/</guid>
      <description> Meta &amp;nbsp; Spring 2019  &amp;nbsp; Lecture  &amp;nbsp; 2019-01-21 
Key Topics &amp;nbsp; ArcGIS Online &amp;nbsp; ArcGIS Pro
Resources &amp;nbsp; View on Syllabus  &amp;nbsp; View on GitHub  &amp;nbsp; Lab-01  &amp;nbsp; Lab-01 Replication 
Videos The following videos replicate the most important skills from Chapter 1 for the course.
Tutorial 1-1    Tutorial 1-2    Tutorial 1-3    Tutorial 1-4    Lab-01 Replication    Discussion Board Threads  Changes to the Labeling Interface  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>