<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SLU SOC 4650 &amp; SOC 5650</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on SLU SOC 4650 &amp; SOC 5650</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Licensed under a CC BY-SA 4.0 License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Geographic Information Science</title>
      <link>/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/</guid>
      <description>Enrollment Closed
SOC 4650 &amp;amp; 5650 is the Department of Sociology and Anthropology&amp;rsquo;s undergraduate and graduate introductory GIS course at Saint Louis University. It is currently offered but enrollment is closed. If you have an interest in the course, you are encouraged to enroll next time it is offered, which will likely be in Spring 2019! This site is for sections taught by Assistant Professor Christopher Prener.
 Course Description This class introduces both the theoretical and technical skills that constitute the nascent field of Geographic Information Science (GISc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Resources</title>
      <link>/course-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course-resources/</guid>
      <description>This page is meant to augment the core documents by providing easy access to online elements of the course. The Syllabus contains a full list of resources, including those not available online.
Core Documents There are two documents for this course that spell out what is required:
 Syllabus Reading List  Course Website This course website will be updated regularly throughout the semester. I&amp;rsquo;ll add a page on the menu for each week, and include links to lecture slides, YouTube videos, and notes about specific topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Onboarding</title>
      <link>/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Before you begin the semester, there are a number of things that you should do to help set yourself up for success. All of the applicable sections below should be completed before our first class on January 22nd. Before you do anything else, though, you should read through the Syllabus and the Reading List. Make sure you have a good sense of what is required for the course. If you have questions, bring them to the first day of class!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Software</title>
      <link>/course-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course-software/</guid>
      <description>Meta 
Overview We rely on several packages that require additional steps to install and use. This section provides details on installing the sf package as well as the development version of ggplot2.
sf sf is a package for working with spatial data in R. It is the most &amp;ldquo;modern&amp;rdquo;, which means it can sometimes be difficult to find examples or help online. This has changed significantly since I first started using it, and the developers are continuing to add vignettes and expand their userbase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Preview</title>
      <link>/course-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course-preview/</guid>
      <description>To set the stage for this semester, please watch the two videos below. These will take approximately 35 minutes to view. Once you have finished these videos, follow the link at the bottom of the page to answer a few short questions about what you saw.
Key Topics  Analysis development   Interactive maps   Open data   Reproducibility 
Open Data and GIS in Los Angeles One of the course learning outcomes is titled &amp;ldquo;GISc and Public Policy&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 01 - Course Introduction</title>
      <link>/lecture-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lecture-01/</guid>
      <description>Meta 
This is our first class meeting, which takes place on January 22nd because of the Martin Luther King, Jr. holiday. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover some administrative material for the course, briefly go over the syllabus, and then start talking about what makes for an effective map. We&amp;rsquo;ll end the night by writing our first lines of R code(!) and making our first maps(!!).
Key Topics  Analysis development   base  Cartography   devtools  Interactive maps   leaflet  magrittr  R  R packages   stlData  utils</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 02 - Working with Data (Part 1)</title>
      <link>/lecture-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lecture-02/</guid>
      <description>Meta 
Key Topics  Analysis development   ggplot2  Git   GitHub  here  knitr  Literate programming   Open data   R  R projects   rmarkdown  stlData
Resources Open on   Exercise - Analysis  Exercise - Plotting  Functions  LP-02  Workflow - Git &amp;amp; GitHub  Workflow - Projects  Workflow - Reprex 
Lecture Slides</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 03 - The Nature of Spatial Data (Part 1)</title>
      <link>/lecture-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lecture-03/</guid>
      <description>Meta 
Key Topics  dplyr  Data types   Data wrangling   here  GIS and policy support   janitor  Levels of measurement   magrittr  naniar  Normalization   R  readr  reprex  Representation   Reproducible Examples   Scale   Spatial autocorrelation 
Resources Open on   Functions  Lab-02  LP-03  PS-01  Workflow - Data Wrangling</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 04 - The Nature of Spatial Data (Part 2)</title>
      <link>/lecture-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lecture-04/</guid>
      <description>Meta 
Key Topics  Analysis development   ArcCatalog  ArcMap  Cartography   Census geography   Coordinate systems   Decision making in GIS   Geodatabases   ggplot2  R  Representation   Representing place   Scale   sf  Shapefiles 
Resources Open on   ArcGIS - ArcCatalog Processes  ArcGIS - ArcMap Processes  Functions  Lab-03  LP-04  PS-02</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 05 - Cartographic Design</title>
      <link>/lecture-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lecture-05/</guid>
      <description>Meta 
Key Topics  ArcMap  dplyr  Cartography   ggplot2  R  RColorBrewer  sf  viridis
Resources Open on   ArcGIS - ArcMap Processes  Functions  Lab-03  LP-05  PS-03 
Lecture Slides  
Lecture Prep 05 Replication    Updates to stlData The stlData package has been updated! You can check out how it has changed by reading through its README.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 06 - GIS Outputs</title>
      <link>/lecture-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lecture-06/</guid>
      <description>Meta 
Key Topics  ArcMap  Cartography   ggplot2  ggthemes  Map Layouts   R  RColorBrewer  Small Multiples   viridis  Wireframing 
Resources Open on   ArcGIS - ArcMap Processes  Functions  Lab-05  LP-06  Map Handouts  Sample Wireframe 
Lecture Slides  
Lecture Prep 06 Replication    Issues with Reading Shapefiles A number of you reported intermittent issues with reading shapefiles into R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 07 - Geodatabases</title>
      <link>/lecture-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lecture-07/</guid>
      <description>Meta 
Key Topics  ArcCatalog  Data wrangling   Geodatabases   lubridate  R  readr  sf  stringr  Writing Data 
Resources Open on   Functions  Lab-06  LP-07 
Lecture Slides  
Re-writing Shapefiles in R Some of you may have been confronted with an error in the lecture prep when you went to knitr your notebook after testing all of its code:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 08 - Demographic Data</title>
      <link>/lecture-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lecture-08/</guid>
      <description> Meta 
Key Topics  Demography   R  sf  tidycensus  tigris
Resources Open on   Example Notebooks  Functions  Lab-07 
Lecture Videos          </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 09 - Spatial Joins</title>
      <link>/lecture-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lecture-09/</guid>
      <description> Meta 
Key Topics  ArcMap  dplyr  R  Spatial Joins   Table Joins   Writing Data 
Resources Open on   ArcMap Processes  Functions  Lab-06  LP-08  PS-05 
Lecture Slides  
Lecture Prep 08 Replication    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 10 - Projections</title>
      <link>/lecture-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lecture-10/</guid>
      <description>Meta 
Key Topics  ArcMap  Geographic coordinate systems   R  sf  Projected coordinate systems   Projecting data 
Resources Open on   ArcMap Processes  Functions  LP-09 
Lecture Slides  
Lecture Prep 09 Replication    Videos From Lecture Scene from The West Wing, Season 2, Episode 16 - &amp;ldquo;The Gall-Peters Projection&amp;rdquo;    Vox.com - &amp;ldquo;Why all world maps are wrong&amp;rdquo;    The True Size The interactive mapping tool described during the lecture - &amp;ldquo;The True Size&amp;rdquo; - can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project</title>
      <link>/final-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/final-project/</guid>
      <description>Core Files Open on   Data  Directions  Groups 
Overview The final project for this course requires students to clean and map non-emergency call data from the City of St. Louis. These data describe the presence of various types of problems in City neighborhoods. The project brings together many of the scientific computing and GI science skills that are developed over the course of the semester. It also models the collaborative nature of GI science work by asking students to complete some aspects of the final project as a group using the collaborative development (GitHub) and communication (Slack) tools we have learned this semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic Index</title>
      <link>/topic-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topic-index/</guid>
      <description>The following is a list of topics and skills covered during the semester. This will grow as we progress through the coursework. Italicized items are only covered in the readings. If you have additions or suggestions, please let Chris know!
A-D  American Community Survey (Lecture-08)  Downlading, see tidycensus  American Fact Finder (Lecture-08) Analysis development (Course Preview, Lectues 01, 02, and 04) Assignment operator, &amp;lt;- (Lecture-01) base, see &amp;ldquo;R, base&amp;ldquo; Broken data connections, repairing (Lecture-04) Cartography  Basic design principles (Lecture-01) Visual hirearchy (Lecture-04)  Centroids (Lecture-09)  Calcuating in ArcGIS Calculating in R, see sf  Coordinate system  EPSG codes (Lecture-10) Geographic coordinate systems (Lecture-10)  and Datums and Ellipsoids NAD 1983 WGS 1984  Overview (Lecture-04) Projected coordinate systems (Lecture-10)  Albers family of equal area projections Lambert family of conic projections State plane system UTM system  Working with in ArcGIS (Lecture-10) Working with in R, see sf  Census geography  Downloading, see tigris (Lecture-08) Overview (Lecture-04)  Coral, Lilian (Course Preview) Data  and levels of measurement (Lecture-03) Data types (Lecture-03) Data wranglng and cleaning (Lecture-03) Open data (Course Preview, Lecture-01) stlData, see &amp;ldquo;stlData&amp;ldquo;  Data frames in ArcGIS (Lecture-04) Demography (Lecture-08) Descartes, Rene (Lecture-10) devtools, see &amp;ldquo;GitHub, Install packages from&amp;ldquo; dplyr, see tidyverse   E-H  Folder connections (Lecture-04) Fonts, see &amp;ldquo;Typography&amp;ldquo; Gauss, Carl Fredrich (Lecture-10) Geodatabases  Overview (Lecture-04)  Geographic coordinate system, see &amp;ldquo;Coordinate system&amp;rdquo; ggplot2, see tidyverse Git (Lecture-02) GitHub  Install packages from with devtools, install_github() (Lecture-01) Integration with Git workflow (Lecture-02)  here - file path management  Create file paths, here() (Lectures 02 and 03)   I-L  Inspecting features in ArcGIS (Lecture-04) Install packages in R  From CRAN, see utils From GitHub, see devtools  Interactive maps  in R with leaflet (Lecture-01), see also &amp;ldquo;leaflet&amp;ldquo; Los Angeles GeoHub (Course Preview)  janitor - data cleaning (Lecture-03)  Duplicate observation analysis, get_dupes() Rename variables en-mase, clean_names()  Layers in ArcGIS (Lecture-04)  Adding and removing Editing symbology Reordering  leaflet, see also &amp;ldquo;Interactive maps&amp;rdquo;  Adding map tiles, addTiles() (Lectures 01 and 10) Adding markers to map, addMarkers() (Lectures 01 and 10) Adding tiles from other providers, addProviderTiles() (Lecture-01) Creating map widget, leaflet() (Lectures 01 and 10)  Literate programming (Lecture-02)  M-P  magrittr, see &amp;ldquo;Pipe operator, %&amp;gt;%&amp;ldquo; Markdown (Lecture-02)  In R, see &amp;ldquo;Markdown&amp;ldquo;  naniar - missing data (Lecture-03)  Missing data analysis by observation, miss_case_summary() Missing data analysis by variable, miss_var_summary()  Navigating map documents (Lecture-04) Normalization (Lecture-03) Open data, see &amp;ldquo;Data&amp;ldquo; Packages, see &amp;ldquo;R, Packages&amp;ldquo; Parker, Hilary (Course Preview) Pipe operator, %&amp;gt;% (Lectures 01 and 03) Projected coordinate system, see &amp;ldquo;Coordinate system&amp;ldquo; Public saftey  Cyclist saftey (Course Preview) Pedestrian saftey (Course Preview)   Q-T  R  base  if-else statements, ifelse() (Lecture-03) get class, class() (Lecture-09) test if vector is character, is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Package Index</title>
      <link>/package-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/package-index/</guid>
      <description>The following is a list of packages used during the semester along with links to additional resources. This list does not include dependencies that may be installed for these packages to work. Unless otherwise noted, packages are available via CRAN and can be installed using base::install.packages(&amp;quot;packageName&amp;quot;).
Icon reference   - Topic index  - CRAN site  - GitHub repo  - Website  - RStudio Cheatsheet  - Book  Base R Packages  base - base functions   stats - statistical functions   utils - utility functions    Data Packages  stlData - St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 20:10:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>Copyright &amp;copy; 2016-2018 Christopher G. Prener
This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
This is a human-readable summary of (and not a substitute for) the license.
You are free to:
 Share — copy and redistribute the material in any medium or format Adapt — remix, transform, and build upon the material, even commercially.  The licensor cannot revoke these freedoms as long as you follow the license terms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>