<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SLU SOC 4650 and 5650 on SLU SOC 4650 and 5650</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SLU SOC 4650 and 5650 on SLU SOC 4650 and 5650</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2019 Christopher G. Prener</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Onboarding</title>
      <link>/docs/course-onboarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/course-onboarding/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;Meta&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;meta-badge semester-sp19&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;far fa-calendar-alt fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Spring 2019&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;meta-badge progress-draft&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-tasks fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Draft&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;meta-badge progress-update&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;far fa-clock fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;2018-12-04&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;btn btn-outline-primary resource&#34; href=&#34;/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Onboarding Checklist &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you begin the semester, there are a number of things that you should do to help set yourself up for success. &lt;strong&gt;All of the applicable sections below should be completed before our first class on January 14th.&lt;/strong&gt; Before you do &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; else, though, you should read through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://slu-soc5650.github.io/syllabus&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Syllabus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Make sure you have a good sense of what is &lt;em&gt;required&lt;/em&gt; for the course. If you have questions, bring them to the first day of class!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;account-signups&#34;&gt;Account Signups&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-started-with-discourse&#34;&gt;Get Started with Discourse&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TBA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-started-with-github&#34;&gt;Get Started with GitHub&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The service that is hosting this website is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. GitHub is used by programmers, data scientists, and researchers for hosting computer code, data, and project materials (like websites). We will be using GitHub extensively this semester. You will need a free account, which you can sign up for one from GitHub&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;. If you already have a GitHub account, you do not need a new one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have a GitHub user name, send Chris a Direct Message via our Discourse site with it so that you can be added to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/slu-soc5650&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SOC 4650 &amp;amp; SOC 5650 organization&lt;/a&gt;. After you have been added to the organization, you should find your assignments repository and check the &lt;strong&gt;Issues&lt;/strong&gt; tab. There should be an open &lt;strong&gt;Issue&lt;/strong&gt; describing how feedback will be disseminated this semester. Please read it and then &lt;em&gt;close the issue&lt;/em&gt; so that we know you&amp;rsquo;ve seen it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-software&#34;&gt;Course Software&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two options for &lt;em&gt;accessing&lt;/em&gt; the course software, and some instructions for how &lt;em&gt;install&lt;/em&gt; it. Please read through these options carefully and make the decision that is best for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;options-for-accessing-software&#34;&gt;Options for Accessing Software&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One option is to rely on the &lt;strong&gt;computers in our classroom&lt;/strong&gt;, and - lucky you(!) - you get 24-hour access to Morrissey Hall for the semester. If you decide to go this route, you can go right to the &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/course-software/&#34;&gt;course software&lt;/a&gt; page to continue setting up your computer - you&amp;rsquo;ll need to install just the specific &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; packages and GitHub Desktop. Details on the extent of setup required will be posted there since it is subject to change. Make sure you know how to use Windows File Explorer, especially if you are a regular macOS user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another option for accessing the software is to &lt;strong&gt;use your own computer&lt;/strong&gt;. If you decide to go this route, please read the next subsection on computer prep, and then head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/course-software/&#34;&gt;course software&lt;/a&gt; page to continue setting up your computer. As long as you have a relatively new computer (within the last few years), you should have no problem using any of the applications for this class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;computer-prep&#34;&gt;Computer Prep&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are using &lt;strong&gt;your own computer&lt;/strong&gt;, you should do the following before proceeding:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make sure your operating system is up-to-date. If you are able, I would also recommend upgrading your computer to the most recent release of its operating system that the computer can run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On macOS, you can do this through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201541&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dummies.com/computers/computer-networking/network-security/how-to-manually-check-for-windows-7-updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Windows 7&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/4027667/windows-update-windows-10&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Windows 10&lt;/a&gt; have system update tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing computer files throughout the semester, so you should ensure that you have functioning anti-virus software and that it is up-to-date. You can get Symantec EndPoint Protection anti-virus software for free from SLU. Go to &amp;ldquo;ITS Software Downloads&amp;rdquo; under &amp;ldquo;Tools&amp;rdquo; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://myslu.slu.edu/tools&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mySLU&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll also need to download files, so you&amp;rsquo;ll need to make sure you have at least &lt;strong&gt;forty gigabytes&lt;/strong&gt; free on your hard drive if you are installing ArcGIS Pro and at least &lt;strong&gt;fifteen gigabytes&lt;/strong&gt; free if you are not. If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure how to check this, here are some instructions for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lifewire.com/how-to-check-free-hard-drive-space-in-windows-2619187&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macworld.com/article/2972775/os-x/how-to-check-your-macs-free-hard-drive-space.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;macOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Options for de-cluttering include deleting files that are no longer needed, moving files to an external device, moving files to a cloud storage system, or upgrading the internal hard drive (may not be possible for macOS users and some Windows users).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make sure you know how to access your computer&amp;rsquo;s file management system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On macOS, this means being comfortable with Finder.app for finding folders, making new ones, and opening files. Here are some tips for using Finder on recent versions of &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201732&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;macOS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Windows, this means being comfortable with Windows File Explorer for finding folders, making new ones, and opening files. Here are some tips for using File Explorer on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dummies.com/computers/operating-systems/windows-7/how-to-navigate-windows-7-with-windows-explorer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Windows 7&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dummies.com/computers/operating-systems/windows-10/how-does-file-explorer-work-in-windows-10/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Windows 10&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/course-software/&#34;&gt;course software&lt;/a&gt; page to continue setting up your computer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-access-to-books&#34;&gt;Get Access to Books&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of different books required for this course. Each book has been selected to correspond with one or more of the course objectives. Please purchase copies of the first three books and decide if you would like a physical copy of the fourth:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brewer, Cynthia. 2015. &lt;em&gt;Designing better Maps: A Guide for GIS users&lt;/em&gt;. Redlands, CA: ESRI Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gorr, Wilpen and Kristen Kurland. 2017. &lt;em&gt;GIS Tutorial 1 for ArcGIS Pro&lt;/em&gt;. Redlands, CA: ESRI Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wickham, Hadley and Garrett Grolemund. 2016. &lt;em&gt;R for data science&lt;/em&gt;. Sebastopol, CA: O’Reilly. &lt;a href=&#34;http://r4ds.had.co.nz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Webbook Available&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the books are available in the bookstore. They can also be ordered online. If you would rather use e-books, those are acceptable for this course as well. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/slu-soc5650/Core-Documents/blob/master/reading-list.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading List&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; includes the assigned readings for both the web and print versions of Wickham and Grolemund&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;R for data science&lt;/em&gt; (2016), and you are free to choose either version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-materials&#34;&gt;Other Materials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other item to purchase is a 1.5&amp;rdquo; three-ring binder (like high school! extra points for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://mentalfloss.com/article/52726/history-trapper-keeper&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Trapper Keeper&lt;/a&gt;!!). While all course materials are available online, they are often easier to use if they are printed. Each week you&amp;rsquo;ll receive various handouts, including (typically) cheat sheets for &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; functions and ArcGIS processes, an illustration of the workflow we are focused on, the lab, and the problem set. The handouts are designed with generous margins to facilitate note-taking on them, and they&amp;rsquo;ll be distributed with holes already punched in them. Keeping these in a three-ring binder will help you refer back to your notes at a later date. You should also purchase dividers, either 16 (one for each week) or 8 (if you want to organize handouts by categories).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;administrative-tasks&#34;&gt;Administrative Tasks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All students should complete the [Student Information Sheet](), which gives me some info about you and gives you the chance to let me know about any initial concerns you might have. It also contains a syllabus agreement, which confirms that you have read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://slu-soc5650.github.io/syllabus&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Syllabus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and understand the course policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;coursework&#34;&gt;Coursework&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three pieces of coursework that you should complete:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should view two videos posted on the &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/course-preview/&#34;&gt;Course Preview&lt;/a&gt; page and check out the interactive map discussed in the first video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should complete &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/course-preview/#lecture-01-entry-ticket&#34;&gt;Lecture-01 Entry Ticket&lt;/a&gt;, which asks a few short questions about the videos and interactive map.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should complete the assigned readings for Lecture-01, which are listed in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://slu-soc5650.github.io/syllabus/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Syllabus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and are available either through &lt;a href=&#34;http://eres.slu.edu/eres/coursepage.aspx?cid=4444&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;electronic reserves site&lt;/a&gt; or through the Course Docs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Preview</title>
      <link>/docs/course-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/course-preview/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;Meta&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;meta-badge semester-sp19&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;far fa-calendar-alt fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Spring 2019&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;meta-badge progress-draft&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-tasks fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Draft&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;meta-badge progress-update&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;far fa-clock fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;2018-12-04&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-topics&#34;&gt;Key Topics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;meta-badge keyword&#34; href=&#34;/docs/topic-index/#a-d&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-tags fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Analysis development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;meta-badge keyword&#34; href=&#34;/docs/topic-index/#i-l&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-tags fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Interactive maps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;meta-badge keyword&#34; href=&#34;/docs/topic-index/#m-p&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-tags fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Open data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;meta-badge keyword&#34; href=&#34;/docs/topic-index/#q-t&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-tags fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Reproducibility&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-data-and-gis-in-los-angeles&#34;&gt;Open Data and GIS in Los Angeles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the course learning outcomes is titled &amp;ldquo;GISc and Public Policy&amp;rdquo;. Much of the data that we will use this semseter is available to us because governmental agencies at the Federal, state, and local levels have published it and made it accessible. We call the movement to make as much data available as possible &amp;ldquo;open data&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different governments have embraced the open data movement to varying degrees, and the video below discusses Los Angeles&amp;rsquo; integration of open data and GIS. It is a 9 minute talk given by L.A.&amp;rsquo;s former Chief Data Officer &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lcoral&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lilian P. Coral&lt;/a&gt;. The talk was part of a conference organized by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.esri.com/en-us/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ESRI&lt;/a&gt;, the makers of ArcGIS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/etdwa768Zms&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve watched the video, check out the web application featured in the video that &lt;a href=&#34;http://ladot.maps.arcgis.com/apps/MapJournal/index.html?appid=a45d3efd7b1d4ef49f362caadb4754b0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;visualizes pedestrian and cyclist injuries in Los Angeles&lt;/a&gt;. You can also visit L.A.&amp;rsquo;s open data website called &lt;a href=&#34;http://geohub.lacity.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GeoHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;analysis-development&#34;&gt;Analysis Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making a produce like L.A.&amp;rsquo;s visualization of pedestrian and cyclist injuries is a complicated effort. Data must be obtained from various sources, modified (a process we call &amp;ldquo;data wrangling&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;data clearning&amp;rdquo;), and then linked with map coordinates. Once it is ready to be mapped, the web application must be designed and created. We&amp;rsquo;ll call this large-scale process a &amp;ldquo;workflow&amp;rdquo; this semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workflow that we&amp;rsquo;ll use is opinionated - there is a strong premise that underlies the workflow about the ways in which spatial data (and data more generally) should be obtained, stored, modified, and mapped. Hilary Parker is a data scientist at &lt;a href=&#34;http://stitchfix.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stichfix&lt;/a&gt; and also runs a data science podcast called &lt;a href=&#34;http://nssdeviations.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Not So Standard Deviations&lt;/a&gt;. She has been speaking recently about an idea called opionated analysis development. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/resources/videos/opinionated-analysis-development/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; linked to below is a 25 minute talk she gave on this idea last year, and she now has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://peerj.com/preprints/3210/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;draft paper&lt;/a&gt; out on the topic as well. Our workflow for this semester is closely linked to the ideas she discusses in this talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/resources/videos/opinionated-analysis-development/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/opinionatedAnalysis.png&#34; alt=&#34;opinionatedAnalysis&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many (but not all of you) will have experienced some parts of these processes before. Perhaps you&amp;rsquo;ve used Microsoft Excel to organize some information or used SPSS to analyze some quantitative data. We won&amp;rsquo;t be using those tools. Instead, this course will emphasize the use of other tools that support reproducibile, accurate, and collaborative data analysis. Thoughout the semester, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss why these tools are important and the advantages they have over other products that are out there. Inspired by Hilary&amp;rsquo;s idea of opinionated analysis development, our goal each week will be to focus on the &lt;em&gt;processes&lt;/em&gt; that can be used to increase the reproducibility and accuracy of our geospatial work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lecture-01-entry-ticket&#34;&gt;Lecture-01 Entry Ticket&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entry ticket for the first lecture asks three follow-up questions about these videos and L.A.&amp;rsquo;s interactive website. Please answer these questions and submit them before class on &lt;strong&gt;January 14th&lt;/strong&gt;. Answers &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; be submitted through &lt;a href=&#34;/&#34;&gt;Google Forms&lt;/a&gt; and each response should be three to four sentances in length. The questions are provided here for reference:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Briefly describe how the City of Los Angeles uses data and mapping to inform how they deliver city services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After viewing the interactive map showing pedestrian and cyclist injuries, describe what you thought of the map. Some example considerations could include: was it easy to read? to navigate? did you like the colors? was it missing relevant data?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your own words, what are the key aspects of opinionated analysis development?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entry ticket also asks for an update on your course onboarding process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Software</title>
      <link>/docs/course-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/course-software/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;Meta&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;meta-badge semester-sp19&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;far fa-calendar-alt fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Spring 2019&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;meta-badge progress-draft&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-tasks fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Draft&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;meta-badge progress-update&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;far fa-clock fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;2018-12-04&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course is built primarily around a set of four software applications - ArcGIS Pro, the programming language &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt;, the graphical user interface for &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; called RStudio, and GitHub Desktop. As I noted on the &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/course-onboarding&#34;&gt;course onboarding page&lt;/a&gt;, there are two choices for &lt;em&gt;accessing&lt;/em&gt; software. Please read through the &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/course-onboarding&#34;&gt;course onboarding page&lt;/a&gt; page carefully and make the decisions you think are best for you - either using your own computer or using a lab computer. Feel free to shoot me an email if you have questions about which approach is best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;arcgis-pro&#34;&gt;ArcGIS Pro&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;ArcGIS Pro is installed in the GIS lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I am able to provide licenses for ArcGIS Pro to students who are interested in obtaining them. If you would like a license, please &lt;a href=&#34;http://pro.arcgis.com/en/pro-app/get-started/arcgis-pro-system-requirements.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;check the system requirements&lt;/a&gt; first. If your computer meets the minimum requirements, email me for a license. Then:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit ESRI&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.esri.com/educationedition&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;education edition website&lt;/a&gt; to begin the process of activating and downloading your ArcGIS Pro Student Trial software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log in using your &lt;strong&gt;Existing Esri account&lt;/strong&gt; (the same one you were given during the &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/course-onboarding&#34;&gt;course onboarding process&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the license code and click Activate ArcGIS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the button for the ArcGIS for Desktop software version being activated - the latest version of ArcGIS Pro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If necessary, download the ArcGIS Uninstall Utility and uninstall previous versions of ArcGIS Desktop or ArcGIS Pro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run the executable file that you downloaded to install ArcGIS Pro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;spatial-libraries&#34;&gt;Spatial Libraries&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;These libraries are installed in the GIS lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There are three open-source spatial libraries that we will indirectly use this semester - GDAL, GEOS, and PROJ.4. They&amp;rsquo;ll be used by the &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; package &lt;code&gt;sf&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;windows&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install the libraries on Windows, you need to have &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/bin/windows/Rtools/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RTools&lt;/a&gt; installed. RTools is a suite of tools for building packages on Windows, and it will allow sf to install a number of spatial data libraries that it requires to read and process shapefiles. These tools require administrative rights, so you may have to enter your password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;macos&#34;&gt;macOS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users on macOS will have to install the spatial data libraries on their own. An omnibus installer is available from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kyngchaos.com/software/frameworks&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kyng Chaos website&lt;/a&gt; - you&amp;rsquo;ll want to download and run the GDAL 2.2 Complete installer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;r&#34;&gt;R&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;installing-base-r&#34;&gt;Installing Base R&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Base R is installed in the GIS lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You can download &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; from its &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.r-project.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. Choose &amp;ldquo;Download R for (Mac) OS X&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Download R for Windows&amp;rdquo;. Windows users should look for text that says &amp;ldquo;install R for the first time&amp;rdquo; and click the &lt;code&gt;base&lt;/code&gt; to the left of that text. Both macOS and Windows users should install &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; version 3.5.1, known as &amp;ldquo;Feather Spray&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you already have &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; installed, please make sure you have the latest version. You can upgrade it using the same process for a new installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;installing-r-packages&#34;&gt;Installing R Packages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-warning&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;R packages will need be installed both in the lab and on personal computers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There are a number of &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; packages that you will need for this semester. If you feel feel comfortable, go ahead and take care of this before the semester starts. If not, we&amp;rsquo;ll go over how to do this type of installation on the first day of class!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following code snipped can be pasted into your &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; console to install all of these required packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;install.packages(c(&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;janitor&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;sf&amp;quot;, 
    &amp;quot;stldata&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;testDriveR&amp;quot;))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on your version of &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; and your operating system, there will be other dependencies that are required and the number of packages installed will be considerably larger. The installation process has not been extensively tested on different operating system and hardware configurations, and though it is unlikely, you may encounter issues. If you do, please let Chris know!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rstudio&#34;&gt;RStudio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;RStudio is installed in the GIS lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;RStudio is a graphical user interface for &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; that will make learning the language and using it much, much easier. You should download the &lt;em&gt;free&lt;/em&gt; version of RStudio from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/#download&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;. Choose the appropriate installer for your platform. Make sure &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; is already installed before installing RStudio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you already have RStudio installed, please make sure you have the latest version. You can upgrade it using the same process for a new installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;github-desktop&#34;&gt;GitHub Desktop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-warning&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;GitHub Desktop will need be installed both in the lab and on personal computers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In addition to the applications above, everyone will need a local installation of GitHub Desktop, which is a graphical user interface for accessing Git and GitHub.com. It can be downloaded for free from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://desktop.github.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;application&amp;rsquo;s website&lt;/a&gt;. You will need to download and run the installer. Once it is complete, you will need to login to the application with your &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/onboarding&#34;&gt;GitHub.com username and password&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you already have GitHub Desktop installed, you should check to make sure you are running the latest version of GitHub Desktop. If you need to update GitHub Desktop, you should also &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/downloads&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;download&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-applications&#34;&gt;Other Applications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download mobile apps for our forum software, Discourse, for both &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwiY686XhYffAhWiVN8KHU64CJYQFjABegQIABAB&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fitunes.apple.com%2Fus%2Fapp%2Fdiscourse-app%2Fid1173672076&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw07B3SNCMe5L2b0byHxYb7p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwiY686XhYffAhWiVN8KHU64CJYQFjAAegQICBAB&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fplay.google.com%2Fstore%2Fapps%2Fdetails%3Fid%3Dcom.discourse%26hl%3Den_US&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw3WxkdpwbRAazq0PByDxG7-&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; devices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project</title>
      <link>/docs/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/project/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;Meta&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;meta-badge semester-sp19&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;far fa-calendar-alt fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Spring 2019&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;meta-badge progress-draft&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-tasks fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Draft&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;meta-badge progress-update&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;far fa-clock fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;2018-12-04&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic Index</title>
      <link>/docs/topic-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/topic-index/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-d&#34;&gt;A-D&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis development (&lt;a href=&#34;/docs/course-preview/&#34;&gt;Course Preview&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;e-h&#34;&gt;E-H&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-l&#34;&gt;I-L&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactive maps (&lt;a href=&#34;/docs/course-preview/&#34;&gt;Course Preview&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;m-p&#34;&gt;M-P&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open data (&lt;a href=&#34;/docs/course-preview/&#34;&gt;Course Preview&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;q-t&#34;&gt;Q-T&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reproducibility (&lt;a href=&#34;/docs/course-preview/&#34;&gt;Course Preview&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;u-z&#34;&gt;U-Z&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing in Markdown</title>
      <link>/docs/markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/markdown/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;Meta&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;meta-badge semester-sp19&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;far fa-calendar-alt fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Spring 2019&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;meta-badge progress-draft&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-tasks fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Draft&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;meta-badge progress-update&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;far fa-clock fa-lg&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;2018-12-04&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;btn btn-outline-primary resource&#34; href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/resources/cheatsheets/#rmarkdown&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; RMarkdown Cheatsheet &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;btn btn-outline-primary resource&#34; href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/rmarkdown-reference.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; RMarkdown Reference Guide &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;basics&#34;&gt;Basics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdown is a simple &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markup_language&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;markup language&lt;/a&gt;. Markup languages are used to give computer programs directions on how particular blocks of text should be processed. Markdown was developed in 2004 by writer and developer &lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;John Gruber&lt;/a&gt;. Gruber describes Markdown on his &lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown is intended to be as easy-to-read and easy-to-write as is feasible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Readability, however, is emphasized above all else. A Markdown-formatted document should be publishable as-is, as plain text, without looking like it’s been marked up with tags or formatting instructions. While Markdown’s syntax has been influenced by several existing text-to-HTML filters — including Setext, atx, Textile, reStructuredText, Grutatext, and EtText — the single biggest source of inspiration for Markdown’s syntax is the format of plain text email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this end, Markdown’s syntax is comprised entirely of punctuation characters, which punctuation characters have been carefully chosen so as to look like what they mean. E.g., asterisks around a word actually look like &lt;em&gt;emphasis&lt;/em&gt;. Markdown lists look like, well, lists. Even blockquotes look like quoted passages of text, assuming you’ve ever used email&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;Markdown’s syntax is intended for one purpose: to be used as a format for writing for the web.
Markdown is utilized to varying degrees by many of the data science tools we&amp;rsquo;ll use in both courses, including RStudio, GitHub, and Slack. In all three applications, Markdown provides a straightforward way to format and stylize plain text files. Markdown therefore gives us the best of two worlds - text files can be organized and formatted as in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WYSIWYG&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;WYSIWYG&lt;/a&gt; editors like Microsoft Word, but they remain plain text files that are accessible in a variety of computing environments and do not depend on proprietary applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdown&amp;rsquo;s simplicity is sometimes also identified as a weakness - it lacks the full fledged control of html or LaTeX, for example. However, for research documentation, the bells, whistles, and fine-grained control of something like LaTeX are unnecessary. Long-term portability is a far more important characteristic, and Markdown excels in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdown files are really just plain-text files, which are usually identified as &lt;code&gt;.txt&lt;/code&gt; files. However, when they contain Markdown syntax, we want to name them as &lt;code&gt;.md&lt;/code&gt; files. Most applications will continue to recognize &lt;code&gt;.md&lt;/code&gt; files as plain-text files. However, certain desktop applications like RStudio and some websites like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub.com&lt;/a&gt; recognize the &lt;code&gt;.md&lt;/code&gt; file extension and will &amp;ldquo;render&amp;rdquo; the Markdown syntax into formatted output. When you create Markdown files in an application like RStudio, make sure to save them with the &lt;code&gt;.md&lt;/code&gt; file extension!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;document-organization&#34;&gt;Document Organization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two principle means for organizing Markdown documents - headings of varying size and paragraph breaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;headings&#34;&gt;Headings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdown contains six heading levels. Headings are identified with &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; symbols and a space that separates them from from the heading text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Input:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;# This is the largest heading
## This is the second largest heading
### This is the third largest heading
#### This is the fourth largest heading
#### This is the second smallest heading
###### This is the smallest heading
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Output:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-paragraphs&#34;&gt;New Paragraphs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leave a blank line between two paragraphs to create a break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Input:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor 
incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Quam pellentesque nec nam aliquam 
sem et tortor consequat. Auctor urna nunc id cursus metus. Eleifend mi in 
nulla posuere. Facilisis sed odio morbi quis. Nibh nisl condimentum id venenatis. 
Lectus nulla at volutpat diam ut venenatis. 

Pretium lectus quam id leo in vitae. Neque vitae tempus quam pellentesque nec nam 
aliquam. Curabitur gravida arcu ac tortor. Arcu risus quis varius quam quisque id 
diam. Viverra aliquet eget sit amet tellus cras adipiscing. Tellus molestie nunc 
non blandit massa enim nec. Tempus imperdiet nulla malesuada pellentesque elit eget. 
Non blandit massa enim nec. Sed risus pretium quam vulputate dignissim suspendisse 
in est ante.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Output:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Quam pellentesque nec nam aliquam sem et tortor consequat. Auctor urna nunc id cursus metus. Eleifend mi in nulla posuere. Facilisis sed odio morbi quis. Nibh nisl condimentum id venenatis. Lectus nulla at volutpat diam ut venenatis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretium lectus quam id leo in vitae. Neque vitae tempus quam pellentesque nec nam aliquam. Curabitur gravida arcu ac tortor. Arcu risus quis varius quam quisque id diam. Viverra aliquet eget sit amet tellus cras adipiscing. Tellus molestie nunc non blandit massa enim nec. Tempus imperdiet nulla malesuada pellentesque elit eget. Non blandit massa enim nec. Sed risus pretium quam vulputate dignissim suspendisse in est ante.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>/talk/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Academic&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further talk details can easily be added to this page using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Project</title>
      <link>/project/external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/external-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal Project</title>
      <link>/project/internal-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/internal-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Duis posuere tellus ac convallis placerat. Proin tincidunt magna sed ex sollicitudin condimentum. Sed ac faucibus dolor, scelerisque sollicitudin nisi. Cras purus urna, suscipit quis sapien eu, pulvinar tempor diam. Quisque risus orci, mollis id ante sit amet, gravida egestas nisl. Sed ac tempus magna. Proin in dui enim. Donec condimentum, sem id dapibus fringilla, tellus enim condimentum arcu, nec volutpat est felis vel metus. Vestibulum sit amet erat at nulla eleifend gravida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nullam vel molestie justo. Curabitur vitae efficitur leo. In hac habitasse platea dictumst. Sed pulvinar mauris dui, eget varius purus congue ac. Nulla euismod, lorem vel elementum dapibus, nunc justo porta mi, sed tempus est est vel tellus. Nam et enim eleifend, laoreet sem sit amet, elementum sem. Morbi ut leo congue, maximus velit ut, finibus arcu. In et libero cursus, rutrum risus non, molestie leo. Nullam congue quam et volutpat malesuada. Sed risus tortor, pulvinar et dictum nec, sodales non mi. Phasellus lacinia commodo laoreet. Nam mollis, erat in feugiat consectetur, purus eros egestas tellus, in auctor urna odio at nibh. Mauris imperdiet nisi ac magna convallis, at rhoncus ligula cursus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cras aliquam rhoncus ipsum, in hendrerit nunc mattis vitae. Duis vitae efficitur metus, ac tempus leo. Cras nec fringilla lacus. Quisque sit amet risus at ipsum pharetra commodo. Sed aliquam mauris at consequat eleifend. Praesent porta, augue sed viverra bibendum, neque ante euismod ante, in vehicula justo lorem ac eros. Suspendisse augue libero, venenatis eget tincidunt ut, malesuada at lorem. Donec vitae bibendum arcu. Aenean maximus nulla non pretium iaculis. Quisque imperdiet, nulla in pulvinar aliquet, velit quam ultrices quam, sit amet fringilla leo sem vel nunc. Mauris in lacinia lacus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suspendisse a tincidunt lacus. Curabitur at urna sagittis, dictum ante sit amet, euismod magna. Sed rutrum massa id tortor commodo, vitae elementum turpis tempus. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Aenean purus turpis, venenatis a ullamcorper nec, tincidunt et massa. Integer posuere quam rutrum arcu vehicula imperdiet. Mauris ullamcorper quam vitae purus congue, quis euismod magna eleifend. Vestibulum semper vel augue eget tincidunt. Fusce eget justo sodales, dapibus odio eu, ultrices lorem. Duis condimentum lorem id eros commodo, in facilisis mauris scelerisque. Morbi sed auctor leo. Nullam volutpat a lacus quis pharetra. Nulla congue rutrum magna a ornare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aliquam in turpis accumsan, malesuada nibh ut, hendrerit justo. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Quisque sed erat nec justo posuere suscipit. Donec ut efficitur arcu, in malesuada neque. Nunc dignissim nisl massa, id vulputate nunc pretium nec. Quisque eget urna in risus suscipit ultricies. Pellentesque odio odio, tincidunt in eleifend sed, posuere a diam. Nam gravida nisl convallis semper elementum. Morbi vitae felis faucibus, vulputate orci placerat, aliquet nisi. Aliquam erat volutpat. Maecenas sagittis pulvinar purus, sed porta quam laoreet at.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website designer for Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Academic&lt;/strong&gt; makes it easy to create a beautiful website for free using Markdown. Customize anything on your site with widgets, themes, and language packs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow our easy &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;step by step guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to build your own free website with Academic. &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/theme/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out the personal demo&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;business demo&lt;/a&gt; of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask a question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Request a feature or report a bug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updating? View the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Update Guide&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support development of Academic:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://paypal.me/cushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Donate a coffee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/cushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Become a backer on Patreon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redbubble.com/people/neutreno/works/34387919-academic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Decorate your laptop or journal with an Academic sticker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.threadless.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wear the T-shirt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easily manage various content including homepage, blog posts, publications, talks, and projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensible via &lt;strong&gt;color themes&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;widgets/plugins&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write in &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; for easy formatting and code highlighting, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; for mathematical expressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social/academic network linking, &lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsive and mobile friendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multilingual and easy to customize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;color-themes&#34;&gt;Color Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Academic is available in different color themes and font themes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-1950s.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;1950s&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-1950s.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-apogee.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Apogee&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-apogee.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-coffee-playfair.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Coffee theme with Playfair font&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-coffee-playfair.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-cupcake.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cupcake&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-cupcake.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-dark.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Dark&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-dark.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-default.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-default.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-forest.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Forest&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-forest.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-ocean.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Ocean&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/getting-started/gallery/theme-ocean.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecosystem&#34;&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-admin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic Admin&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; An admin tool to import publications from BibTeX or import assets for an offline site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-scripts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic Scripts&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Scripts to help migrate content to new versions of Academic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;install&#34;&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can choose from one of the following four methods to install:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one-click install using your web browser (recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer using Git with the Command Prompt/Terminal app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer by downloading the ZIP files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer with RStudio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;quick-install-using-your-web-browser&#34;&gt;Quick install using your web browser&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.netlify.com/start/deploy?repository=https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Install Academic with Netlify&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Netlify will provide you with a customizable URL to access your new site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On GitHub, go to your newly created &lt;code&gt;academic-kickstart&lt;/code&gt; repository and edit &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; to personalize your site. Shortly after saving the file, your site will automatically update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to add Markdown content. For inspiration, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown content&lt;/a&gt; which powers the &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/theme/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-git&#34;&gt;Install with Git&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/downloads&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download and install Git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/installing/#quick-install&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download and install Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart#fork-destination-box&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fork&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;em&gt;Academic Kickstart&lt;/em&gt; repository and clone your fork with Git:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart.git My_Website
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that if you forked Academic Kickstart, the above command should be edited to clone your fork, i.e. replace &lt;code&gt;sourcethemes&lt;/code&gt; with your GitHub username.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initialize the theme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd My_Website
git submodule update --init --recursive
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-zip&#34;&gt;Install with ZIP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart/archive/master.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; and extract &lt;em&gt;Academic Kickstart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/archive/master.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; and extract the &lt;em&gt;Academic theme&lt;/em&gt; to the &lt;code&gt;themes/academic/&lt;/code&gt; folder from the above step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-rstudio&#34;&gt;Install with RStudio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-rstudio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the guide to installing Academic with RStudio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;quick-start&#34;&gt;Quick start&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you installed on your computer, view your new website by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;localhost:1313&lt;/a&gt; and your new Academic powered website will appear. Otherwise, if using Netlify, they will provide you with your URL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to add Markdown content, customize your site, and deploy it. For inspiration, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown content&lt;/a&gt; which powers the &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/theme/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build your site by running the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command. Then &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com/create-your-website-with-hugo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;host it for free using Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; or Netlify (refer to the first installation method). Alternatively, copy the generated &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; directory (by FTP, Rsync, etc.) to your production web server (such as a university&amp;rsquo;s hosting service).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;updating&#34;&gt;Updating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;em&gt;star&lt;/em&gt; the project on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; to help keep track of updates and check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; prior to updating your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before updating the framework, it is recommended to make a backup of your entire website directory (or at least your &lt;code&gt;themes/academic&lt;/code&gt; directory) and record your current version number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, Academic is installed as a Git submodule which can be updated by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;git submodule update --remote --merge
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out the update guide&lt;/a&gt; for full instructions and alternative methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feedback-contributing&#34;&gt;Feedback &amp;amp; Contributing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt; to let me know about any bugs or feature requests, or alternatively make a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For support, head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo discussion forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-present &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Person Re-Identification System For Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>/publication/person-re-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/person-re-id/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile visual clothing search</title>
      <link>/publication/clothing-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/clothing-search/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>/slides/example-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slides/example-slides/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-slides&#34;&gt;Welcome to Slides&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;porridge = &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;
if porridge == &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;:
    print(&amp;quot;Eating...&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = \;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  Three
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
- Only the speaker can read these notes
- Press `S` key to view
{{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/img/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; slide background-image=&amp;quot;/img/boards.jpg&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide background-color=&amp;quot;#0000FF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide class=&amp;quot;my-style&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;.reveal section h1,
.reveal section h2,
.reveal section h3 {
  color: navy;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
